so how to take your first trade step by
step by the end of this video you're
going to be able to take your first
trade in the real market so you can
start making money immediately imagine
that the first time you learn trading
with one YouTube video of one hour
you're literally about to take your
first trade by the end of this video to
make money in the markets so if you're
watching this right now you probably
know what trading is or you have an idea
or you're not really have Clarity of how
to actually take a trade or how to go
about it this video is going to explain
to you exactly everything in extreme
detail because I'm sure you've watched a
couple of other videos and you want to
get into it and you have an idea but you
don't have the actual core answer of how
it works so I've prepared this video for
you so I can show you how to take your
first trade in the financial markets and
I'm going to show you a step by step on
how to do it actually before you take
the trade how you analyze the market how
you use the analysis to enter the market
how you withdraw the money how you take
it to your bank account and how you
compound your interest on your money so
you become a profitable Trader like me
and everybody around me so if you stick
around to the end of this video and you
watch every single detail I can
guarantee you that you're going to be
one step closer to becoming a profitable
Trader offering these step by step on
how to execute your trade and how to
trade in the financial markets so now
before we get started there might be a
chance you might get lost in the steps
of how to take the trade so before
making your first trade you have to make
sure you have enough information about
the market so you know exactly what
you're doing so if I any point in this
video you seem to get lost just come
back to the beginning and watch this
video right here where it goes into
detail on every single topic that we're
going to be talking about today in
addition to what I'm explaining today
which is the step by- step on how to
execute the trades in the market so now
let's get into the video so what is
Forex right well first of all Forex is
short for foreign exchange so this is
the market where it's buyers versus
Sellers and this is where you're
basically buying one currency against
the other or you're selling one currency
against the other and prices are
fluctuating up and down sometimes the
USD is stronger than the cad sometimes
the pound is stronger than the USD and
in that fluctuation there's a spread
there's literally price Movement by
decimals that goes up and down and that
is where we make our profit in those
decimal points that price moves up or
down and this is where buyers come into
the market and they push price up and
then here's where sellers come into the
market and they push price down so what
we look for is to just hop into the
trend if the majority of the buyers are
going up we buy with them if the
majority of the markets are going down
the sellers we're going with them and
then you might ask how do we actually
make the money like where does the money
come from it can't come from thin air
and the money comes from other Traders
in the market I say about 80 to 90% of
the Traders in the market are wrong all
of the time especially retail Traders
that's where our money comes from
because people that lose money in the
markets somebody else has to make that's
why it's so key to have a profitable
strategy because if you know what's
going to happen let's say 60 70% of the
time with a positive risk to reward
you're going to make money consistently
in the market while other Traders are
consistently losing money in the markets
and there's many advantages to Forex
Trading like no other you guys even have
no idea if you're comparing this to any
other business in Industry this is the
most profitable industry that you can
possibly ever start in here you don't
have to deal with clients you don't have
to deal with shipping you don't have to
deal with product customer reviews you
don't have to deal with any headaches of
the actual operation of running a
business you don't have to deal with any
issues that can happen with the business
whether you're selling a product whether
you're managing a store whether you're
even managing somebody else's store all
you need in trading Forex is money and
sometimes you don't even have to use
your own money once you become
profitable you can seek funding and you
can use other people's money to make
money in the markets as crazy as this my
sound but more of this towards the end
of the video after you already know how
to take your first trade in the market
so you can get funded as well all right
so now we're going to get started onto
trading view so this is the actual
platform where you're going to see the
markets that you're going to be trading
in real time this is where I say 99% of
Traders look at the markets trading view
is a very World known platform very
simple It's very effective and I'm going
to show you guys of how to actually sign
up how to get started and how to have
your markets look exactly like mines so
you can start getting results like mine
as soon as possible so this is
tradingview.com you guys can pretty much
just come here and then you just create
an account and the way you create an
account is you simply come here and
click get started as soon as you get
started you would obviously have to sign
up and it's free do not get the payment
option right now you don't need that it
is extremely unnecessary so you come
here you click sign up and it's going to
ask you to sign into your account and
pretty much create it so for this
example purposes we're going to sign up
with our Google account so we can log in
and show you the different options
trading view has to offer so after you
sign up it's going to ask you here to
create a username this if you want to
connect to Traders on the platform I've
personally never done it and I've been
here for pretty much six years trading
is supposed to only be you and yourself
so you pretty much create your account
create the name and you just click next
and then you sign in and as soon as you
sign in it's going to show you these
different options of plans that they
have to offer you don't need these right
now this is just to either remove the
ads that pop up or to add some alarms or
to add a bunch of extra stuff that
realistically you don't need you just
need the charts that they're already
going to give to you for free so in
order for you to see those charts you
have to come over here to markets and
then you have to click overview once you
head over to the markets and you click
overview it's going to automatically
create you a watch list so this will be
your watch list up here to the top right
so these are going to be the currency
pairs the different type of markets that
you're going to be analyzing so you
execute your trade so automatically it's
going to create for you different tabs
it's going to create you a indices tab
it's going to create you a stocks tab if
you scroll down it's going to create you
a Futures Tab and then it can also
create a Forex tab so we're here
personally to trade Forex so we
realistically we don't need the other
tabs so let's actually go in and clean
up and fix all of this so you click here
on EUR USD which is obviously the most
known Market in the world and then you
click here see on super charts as soon
as you click see on super charts a new
tab will be opened up and this is where
you're going to spend 99% of your time
to analyze the markets on trading view
this is going to be a spot where
everything is done so you no longer need
this first tab so you can pretty much
just exit out of this tab right here and
then if you notice your watch list still
remains here as well so for right now
let's move this to the downside so we
can have some moving area so we're
actually able to have this Market show
what we want and show the markets that
we want to show so let's actually move
this to the downside and you guys can
see here these are all the different
type of markets that trading view has
given us so we're going to come in here
and fix all that very fast all right so
first of all we're going to remove the
stocks we don't need stocks so you just
simply just click that we're going to
remove all of these different types of
you know markets that we don't use we're
going to remove the stock section all of
this right we don't trade none of this
so we don't need it except gold but
we'll add that later down the road
remove silver and then we're left with
our Forex pairs right so got that clean
that up you have only have to focus on
what matters so next is these charts
right here I personally have everything
set up a very specific and precise way
so the body of the candlesticks they
have to be blue to head up
and then red for them to head down the
borders have to be black cuz you have to
be able to identify the close and the
open of the candlesticks so we make that
black and then the Wicks obviously have
to be black so you can see them happen
in real time in the markets now you
might not see it right now of all of
these black points and that is because
obviously our background is bright is
black that's where we're going to go
over to the actual canvas and we're
going to make it white and then next we
change that black background you can
actually see the candlesticks and you
have a textbook style of chart you come
here to the background and then you're
going to put it white a lot of people
they like having it a lot of different
types of ways I like going the texture
route I like going the very simple and
effective route so I have my
candlesticks black bodies and Wicks uh
blue bodies to head up red bodies to
head down so this exactly how I have my
markets in real time we don't need this
price down here so simply you just
double click it you click that right
here and then you go to style and you
simply remove the volume you don't need
that that is extremely pointless in the
market so as of right now this is
exactly what my market would look like
this is how you would need to have your
charts to trade like me and have results
like me so you can have the same type of
Market recognition once you see the
market so now that you have your USD GBP
USD and USD JPY you want to make sure
you're on the right server so as of
right now we're on fxcm server so this
is not the best server because sometime
there's gaps in the market as you see
right right here you come over here
there's a little Gap in the market right
here and for a beginner Trader this can
be very very confusing and it can be you
know it could just cause confusion it
can mess up your trading as you see gaps
right here so what we want to do is we
just want to get onto the keyboard we
want to type Euro USD and then here we
want to go to the oanda server so as you
can see this is the fxtm server and then
we go to the oanda server and you guys
can see how that Gap right there on fxcm
it is no longer there because now we are
on the oand the server so if I simply
click this option right here that is
back at the fxcm server you can see how
the markets have gaps they just look
weird versus if once again if we look
for the Euro USD on the oanda server you
can see how it is there so what we want
to do is we want to come here and we
want to flag that option and you want to
flag it as red so as soon as you flag it
as red it's going to add it to your
watch list after you come here and then
you add it and now to see that market
that it's actually flagged you simply
come up here to the watch list and then
you just click red and then this will be
your red watch list and as you can see
once we click on this server now we are
on the oand the server you can see how
the gaps get filled Market is beautiful
so this is the perfect example of how my
markets are I just have many different
types of markets for example gbpusd on
the o server pretty much just click here
the red and it's already automatically
added to my watch list We'll add AUD CAD
same thing we're make sure we're on the
oand the server come here we just flag
it once we flag it automatically Al pops
up here on my watch list I've done this
for about 15 different pairs that I
actively trade but more on that on
another video I want to make sure you
guys are ready to take your first trade
by the end of this video so this is
trading view trading view is where
you're going to analyze your Market this
is where you're going to see if the
market is headed up or if the market is
headed to the downside so you could
actually enter the trade with the trend
of the market so you can make money and
that is very key to the next point that
I'm going to be explaining very very
very soon so the next platform that
we're going to enter is metatrader
there's metatrader 4 and there's met
five SO trading view is where you
actually analyze the market this is
where you see the market and you
actually take a trade based off of what
that is showing you now where do you
take the trade will you take the trade
on metatrader 4 or metatrader 5 there's
other platforms out there but I'd say
90% of the actual industry trades on
metatrader 4 and metatrader 5 I've never
used any other platform other than
metatrader 4 metat Trader 5 so I
recommend stick to them it's very simple
and they have things straight to the
point and it is very very effective and
the majority of the brokers in the
industry use metatrader 4 metatrader 5
because once again everybody uses
metatrader 4 metatrader 5 so both of
these apps are actually on the App Store
metat trator 4 is obviously to the left
metat trator 5 is obviously to the right
metat trator 4 you have an idea is like
the iPhone 14 metat Trader 5 is like the
new iPhone 15 or the newest version of
the iPhone they both work perfect just
metat Trader 5 is a little bit newer so
for this video example I'm going to be
showing you how it looks like on metat
Trader 5 but the buttons are exactly the
same on metat Trader 4 as they are on
metatrader 5 so we're going to click
here on metat Trader 5 and the first
thing once you come in you can see that
our trade button down in the middle this
is where you can see the balance the
equity and the actual free margin of
your account for now we're going to make
an account real quick so I can show you
guys how to look at this app and how to
actually take a trade from it so first
let's start off from the right button
which is the settings on the account so
what we're going to do is we're going to
click all the way at the top where it
says new account which is the second to
First Option once we click on the new
account we're going to create a new
broker login and we're just going to use
the meta quotes login right just for
this example purposes so right now we're
just going to register an account so
we're going to click the top button
which says register a new account we're
going to create a demo account just for
this account purposes so we're going to
click that option right there you're
going to be able to fill in your first
name your last name your phone number
and then your email right obviously my
information is blurred out um but then
after that you can just click the server
is going to obviously be meta quotes the
account will be a Forex hedge account
and then you need more than a leverage
for the deposit amount you can
realistically do whatever amount you
want so realistically start off with a
realistic amount so let's just put
$5,000 as the base of the account once
you click on that then you come and you
click the accept button and this is
where you accept the terms and
conditions and you register the account
so then here's where you're simply going
to go and then you're going to click
Start soon as you click Start the market
is going to automatically begin and then
you can see how the account is currently
being loaded cuz it's actually created
you a demo account so you can trade the
live markets but with a demo account
which is also known as paper trading
which is just so you get a feel of how
the actual platform works the market
conditions they have to offer and you
just practice your trading without
risking any actual real money now that
we have our account you can see up here
it shows you the meta quote software the
corporation and then that is is a demo
account so let's head all the way to the
left which is the quotes section so
right here this might look intimidating
this might look that there's a lot going
on but there's actually not this is
actually very simple and very
straightforward so the first thing that
you see is those numbers fluctuating
these numbers all the way over here to
the right the first one is EUR USD and
it has 1.05 476 and that number is
constantly moving up and down and the
number next to is 1.05 48 and then that
number next to the the little number is
always fluctuating moving up and down so
this is the real time price of the
market this is the market fluctuating
right in front of you and then this is
basically the difference between the
spread what they were asking versus the
market there's a whole other video on
that right but this is just very simple
purposes if you head over to the left of
it you can see that this is Euro USD so
Euro USD is the currency pair that we
would be trading on this market right
here so if we were to click it it would
give us the option to trade it look at
the chart see details statistics or the
depth of the market the only button you
need to focus on here is the trade
button because this is where you're
going to actually execute a trade on the
market but before we do that let me
actually explain a little bit more so
let's say for example you don't want to
trade USD JPY or the USD chn you pretty
much click the pen all the way at the
top right corner once you click that pen
you can select the markets you don't
want to trade and then you can pretty
much just trash them right but let's say
you trash some markets for the wrong
reason you can just click on the search
bar and then as soon as you click on the
search bar you can just search them up
again USD chn and then you just click
the plus sign and as you can see it is
back here at the the bottom so nothing's
ever going to disappear on this platform
everything will always be here on the
market there's actually two different
ways on how to see this actual currency
Pairs and how the market are fluctuating
and that is with the button all the way
at the top left corner and as you can
see there it pretty much shows you the
symbol shows you the bid the ask price
and then the daily percentage so this is
a very much more simplified option
compared to the other one the other one
might look a little bit more
intimidating I personally always use it
just because it shows you the numbers
big right in front of your face so I can
see the spread that the BR ERS offering
you at that point in time so this is
also a very simple point to do it but
both do exactly the same thing let's say
I want to trade EUR USD I click it and
it gives me the same exact option next
we have the chart option so this is
where you can actually see the charts of
the trade so for example let's say we
wanted to trade EUR USD you guys can see
here how the eurusd chart that we are
watching on trading view we can actually
see it on metatrader 5 so this chart is
the same exact thing as trading view but
it's a little bit more more let's say
old it's outdated you can't have as much
Freedom as you do on trading view so
this is why we trade and mark up our
trades on trading View and we actually
execute the markets on metat Trader 4
and metat Trader 5 so this chart option
you pretty much don't really have to see
it unless you want to just you know take
a screenshot that you're in a trade and
just post it on social media and show
your friends that you're making money
next is the actual trade button and this
is where probably a lot of you guys have
seen this right you've seen a lot of
blue numbers a lot of red numbers this
is where you can actually your trade
floating and profit or floating and loss
this is where the p&l of your actual
account is and this is where the money
is in the metat trader platform so you
can actually execute the trades into the
real Market next is the history tab so
this is where you can see all of the
positions you've taken in the past so
you can see the positions that you've
won the positions that you've lost and
the details behind those positions you
can also see some orders that you have
and then the deal and so on and so forth
but the main button you're going to be
using here is the position let's say you
want to see six months worth of data cuz
you want to show an investor you want to
show a family member you want to show a
friend you pretty much click the clock
at the top right and you can show 6
months 3 months a week whatever you want
you could even organize it by the
symbols that you want to show at that
very time and then once again the button
all the way to the right is the actual
settings button so this is a very very
simple platform to use I've been using
it for about to be six years now at the
end of this year and it is where you're
going to spend the majority of your time
when it comes to executing your trade
you're going to spend more time on
actual trading view to analyze a trade
because all you have to do is come into
this app right here to just execute the
trade this broker is going to give you
the option to actually execute the
market in real time it's going to give
you the option to enter the market
immediately that is what metatrader does
metatrader is the person that connects
you directly to the market the broker is
the middleman so you're the retail
Trader and then you want to enter the
real Market you can't just go directly
into the market there has to be that
middleman the middleman is the broker
the broker is the one that connects you
to the market and they charge a spread
they charge Commission
and they have deposit and withdraw fees
that is their business model on how they
make money to connect you to the market
so you can execute the trades and you
make money from Trading so these Brokers
that are going to actually execute you
into the market there's hundreds if not
thousands of them out there and
everybody always ask me what broker do
you recommend and I don't like
recommending a broker because personally
everybody out there has a different
taste in their trading some platforms
are better than others some platforms
have better moments than others so
that's why I always recommend do your
due diligence but I would recommend you
to the top three most known brokers in
the industry and they're regulated and
everybody across the board knows them so
the first broker is going to be
forex.com crazy name right it's
literally forex.com they're regulat
platform where you can execute trades
the next one is oanda.com oanda.com is a
platform that I first started trading
that is where I deposited my first real
money into the account and they work
very very well they have regular credit
card deposit debit card deposit they
even accept wire transfer and I think
they have added crypto deposits into the
platform as well and then third is going
to be IC markets so IC markets is a
regulated platform um I think in the
European and it is a very very
well-known platform like let's say
binance across the world so IC markets
is another platform that they also have
metat Trad 4 and metatrader 5 as options
to execute into the market I've never
use them but I know they're very very
well known so these are the three
trusted platforms that I recommend to
use with meta Trader 4 metat Trader 5
and you need one of these platforms you
have to use a broker in order to you
execute to the real Market there's no
way that a retail Trader can go straight
to the real Market by just connecting to
it it's not going to happen you have to
have the broker in the middle that gets
the actual asking price of the market
and then you send the money to the
broker and the broker connects it to the
market and they charge their fees to
make that trade be able to happen so now
we're going to actually take a trade
together right now but I'm not going to
just go on the Met Trader 4 and metat
Trader 5 and just execute a trade I'm
going to actually show you guys a little
bit of my strategy I'm going to show you
guys the different types of ways that
you can make money trading you can make
money trading with technical analysis
with price action support and resistance
EMA Trend continuation all of this stuff
and my strategy is a combination of all
of this and trust me this might sound
like a lot of information but 5 and a
half six years ago I was at Dunkin
Donuts and I didn't know any of this
stuff I didn't go to college I barely
graduated high school and I am
considered a professional Trader
nowadays just because of trial and error
and because I never gave up so I'm going
to teach you guys a pretty simple
version of this so you guys understand
it don't get intimidated by all of these
lines and don't get intimidated by all
of these candlesticks they're very very
simple and as soon as you understand it
it's you're going to have a huge aha
moment so I'm going to show you guys
right now how to execute a trade on
metat Trader 5 so you can do it yourself
but I don't want you to go do it
yourself without any context I want to
make sure you have an idea of what
you're doing before you take this trade
so I'm going to show you guys a little
bit of my strategy so let me actually go
back and dive in to show you guys how
I'm going to take this trade all all
right so let's head back here to EUR USD
right so this is the euro dollar versus
the US dollar so let's say that we're
going to buy this Market that doesn't
mean you're going to buy the Euro and
you're going to sell the dollar or let's
say we're going to sell this Market that
doesn't mean you're going to sell the
dollar and buy the Euro that's not how
this works basically what you're doing
is you're betting that price is going to
go up or you're betting that price is
going to go down so if we're looking to
buy this Market that means we're looking
to bet that the euro is going to get
stronger than the US dollar and this is
something very key to understand because
this can maybe cause a lot of confusion
for beginner Traders and it's very
simple you can identify whether the
market is going to go up or down simply
by the trend of the market so as you can
tell as of right now this market right
here overall the trend is headed to the
downside you can see how this Market is
creating lower lows and lower highs as
of right now it's actually bullish this
Market structure it's potentially going
to shift to the upside because we have a
head and shoulders but that's a little
bit more advanced in the video I'm just
going to keep it very simple and just
continue trading with the trend to what
a beginner can look at this market like
right so for example this market right
here is headed to the downside so the
first thing in my strategy and any
strategy realistically is Trend you need
to know where is the market headed is
the market headed to the upside or is
the market headed to the downside
because if you know where the market is
headed that makes trading a whole lot
easier right it's already a 50/50 the
market can only go up or it can go down
so if you're eliminates one other option
that makes the odds of you making money
trading a whole lot easier so that's why
if you understand that the market is
headed to the downside you only look for
sales that makes the odds of you making
money a whole lot easier so for this
example right here on EUR USD if we're
going to be looking for sell we're going
to be betting that this chart is going
to be going down we're going to be
betting that the euro is going to get
weak and that the dollar is going to get
strong this is what we're going to be
doing on Euro USD today now in order to
identify that the market is headed to
the downside we're using Market
structure Market structure are all of
these points right here literally every
single point that you see on this market
right now is considered Market structure
this structure point right here is a
market structure point this point right
here is considered a market structure
points so every single point on this
Market is actual Market structure so
Market structure are all of these points
up here these are points where Market is
creating also known as an elbow in the
market this is where the market shows
you that it's rejecting that area and it
doesn't like that zone so this is the
market structure Market structure Market
structure Market structure Market
structure so people say that they trade
market structure pretty say they pretty
much trade markets they pretty much
trade the chart it can be very confusing
at first because if you don't know the
definition of it it could just be like
well what is market structure well
you're looking at Market structure is
just price now some people say they
trade candlesticks well you're looking
at all the Candlestick this is a
Candlestick this is a Candlestick this
is a Candlestick every single red or
blue box that you see is a Candlestick
in the market so yes we trade market
structure which is the price of the
currency pair and we trade candlesticks
which is what shows us what the price of
the currency pair is you guys are seeing
how I'm making such a complicated topic
so simple and narrow down because that's
the reality of the situation and then
next is support and resistance oh you
trade support and resistance and that is
yes I do trade support and resistance
because it is the floor and then it is
the roof so in order for me to enter a
trade I need to pretty much buy it at a
support which is also known as a floor
and I need to sell it at a roof also
known as a resistance so what we do is
we get price that tends to use certain
areas as a level of support and
resistance let me show you what I mean
by this so a level of support is
identified by an area that price is
clearly rejecting from so for example
let's use this line chart right here to
identify this as a level of support so
pretty much every single time price
comes to this level of support price
rejects it and then it just heads to the
upside or it just decides to reject it
this is also known as a support level so
a zone that has more than three touches
that rejects as the level of support is
known as a valid area of support so this
is what it would look like at a support
level so what we do as Traders and as
very simple and effective trading
strategy what we do is pretty much once
price comes to the support area we look
to buy and we don't look to buy just
because it is at a level of support we
have a series of confluences that add up
and that is well first of all the
majority of the market is actually
headed to the upside so the market is
headed to the upside and then we're
rejecting this level of support so that
means the most logical thing we should
be doing is buying so that's an example
of how we use support to enter a trade
but for this example if the market is
actually headed to the downside then we
need to use it as a resistance area and
it's very simple it's just vice versa
that means that price is reaching pretty
much a ceiling of price and every single
time price gets back to this area it
rejects it and then it heads to the
downside this is where we would look to
then sell a price because the market is
no longer interested in buying and the
market is headed to the downside so
we're going to be looking for sells to
continue the trend of the market so for
this example right here this is what is
the area of resistance would look like
and we will be looking to sell this
again very simple very effective just to
remove all the noise of what the market
actually consists of and looks like
right so let's spot a level of support
that is going to be used as resistance
so obviously we can tell this Market is
headed to the downside so we're just
going to Simply look to the left and
we're going to see well where is this
level of support and resistance so we're
going to get our trusty box over here
and then once we get our trusty box
we're going to simply just Zone it up at
this spot right here and we're going to
drag it to the right and you guys can
see how this is used as support one two
and then three times so this is a valid
area of support and it is used as
resistance as well meaning that this is
a valid area of support and resistance
so whenever we're headed to the upside
and we're Above This Zone we're buying
whenever we're headed to the downside
and we're under the Zone we are selling
that is the Simplicity of this trade so
literally the two factors that I
explained that I look to take my trade
which is Trend and sell at a resistance
we have that on this trade right here so
let's suppose that we are going to take
this trade right here so in order to
execute this trade we need to now go
back to metatrader 5 and actually take
the trade right but before that we need
to see our risk to reward ratio right
what are we risking versus what are we
going to gain so this is where we come
here I click this button I drag down the
stop loss stop loss we just put around
this area for now this is all just for
examples purposes and then we have the
takeprofit zone right here so as you
guys can see here on the risk to reward
ratio button this tells us where we're
going to get out of price if we lose and
this is going to tell us what we're
going to get out of price if we win and
this is actually very perfect and very
accurate because your risk is calculated
so you never are going to lose more than
what you expect to lose because you're
going to pre-calculate your risk and
then you're never going to gain more
than what you expect to gain because
you're going to pre-calculate your gain
as well and this is something that I
realize that this is the edge in the
market once you learn this and once you
figure this out you pretty much have an
edge over the market because you know
what you're going to risk and every
single time you risk something you're
always going to make more of it and
that's what is this risk to reward ratio
is for so this right here is the risk to
reward ratio so for example let's say
you're risking $10 so in this red box
like's suppose that price goes directly
into your stop loss I mean from the
second you enter the trade it runs
straight into what you were obviously
willing to lose let's say price hits
that area directly from the instant you
take it you're going to only lose $10
even if price goes all the way up here
you stop price right here this is where
you got out of the market so the $10
that you risk are gone but now let's say
price goes the other way which is the
continuation of the trend under the
resistance level which gives you a high
probability trade and let's say price
goes over here price is now going to
give you $20 because you have a one to2
risk to reward so you're risking $10 to
gain $20 and that is a positive risk
reward and this is actually very
interesting because you can have a risk
reward pretty much up to whatever you
want I've had trades that hit up up to a
1 to 17 risk meaning I risk $10 to then
gain
$170 so it's a very low risk with very
very big gain so you just keep moving
this down and you can see how the risk
reward ratio keeps getting bigger and
bigger now the risk reward ratio is a 1
to four I keep moving it down now it is
a 1 to five so obviously this varies
based off of takeprofit zones and that
stuff but that is as well for another
video I just want you to understand the
core of the actual risk reward and how
it works because now when we're going to
take this trade and we're going to
actually execute it we have to plug in
these numbers right here so what we're
going to do now is we're going to head
back over to metat Trader 5 on the
account that we just created together
and we're going to actually execute this
trade together in real time markets you
guys can see right here that there is
currently 6 hours and 54 minutes left on
this Candlestick with 50 seconds that
it's always fluctuating and you know
it's a countdown uh that we're real
Market we're live right now on the
market it is currently Tuesday morning
at 10:00 a.m. so what we're going to do
is we're going to head now to metat
Trader 5 and we're going to take this
trade together all right so now that
we're here on metat Trader 5 we're going
to click the app and then the first
thing that's going to pop up is the
quotes depends where you last left it
doesn't really matter you can just go
back to it right so we're going to go to
the advanced setting on the metat trader
5 so as you can tell the first currency
prayer that pops up is your USD which is
the same one that we were analyzing on
trading view so what you want to do in
order to enter this trade is just tap it
so once you tap on that currency prayer
it's going to give you different options
to enter the trade so this is where
you're going to click the actual trade
option so this is where you're going to
click trade and as soon as you click
trade it's going to give you this option
of the euro versus the US dollar so
before we actually plug in the trade and
we put the stoploss the take profit
everything else we want to see what type
of Market we want to do so we click the
little arrow right next to instant
execution it's going to give you
different types of Market executions you
can use a buy limit sell limit buy stop
sell stop buy stop limit sell stop limit
all of this stuff we're going to only
use instant execution because we want to
enter Market immediately now right we
want to enter this very second you want
to enter based off of what the market is
showing us as of right now so we're
going to Simply select that option and
that is what I use 100% of the time that
I enter the trades in the market I don't
want to put a market limit I don't want
to put a market order other people use
that but the way I see it is like if
you're going to place a market order in
the market that means you're not
entering the trade based off of
probability you're just entering a trade
based off of price that gets there and
sometimes price get start doesn't give
you your entry signal doesn't give you
your confirmation so you pretty much
just wasted a trade and it wasn't a high
probability trade so for right now we're
going to only use instant execution next
we have the lot size so this right here
you can pretty much put whatever lot
size you want you can put two lots you
can put five Lots whatever Lots you want
to put and this is where you're going to
risk actual money on the $5,000 account
so if we actually head back really fast
you have $5,000 on this account so you
want to pre-calculate how much money
you're with link to risk from this
account to actually take this trade so
once we come here and we click the trade
and I go to the lot size this lot size
has to be appropriate to the stop loss
because in the stop loss there's points
so let's say there is 20 points and
let's say you have a five lot for the
five lot that means you're risking $50
per point because a decimal points on
the five lot it moves over so that means
you're risking $50 per point so if you
have a 50 lot and then you have 20
points as your stop loss that means that
we would be risking $1,000 on that trade
now that is literally 20 to 25% of the
account cuz obviously you might get a
little bit more a little bit less
depends of the actual spread that the
broker is going to charge you you can
risk $1,000 on the trade but the broker
is going to charge you money for
executing that trade so it can sometimes
be a little bit more a little bit less
depends on how the actual market
conditions are actually before we enter
this trade let's go back to trading view
let's set the right risk management so
we come back here and we risk the amount
that we're okay with losing so now that
we're back here in the market let's
actually calculate the lot size right so
a lot of people say what's the right lot
size how do I know which one's the right
one and there's never a right one it
always changes because you're going to
always risk a different amount on each
trade if that's what you like and each
lot size is different because each pair
is different this is all going to make
so much sense right now it's really not
that complicated so once you come over
here to back to trading view you want to
calculate how much you're going to risk
so this is where I always head over to
babypips.com and and then I click here
on the position size calculator this
literally does all of the work for you
so now that we're here in the position
size calculator this literally does all
the work for you it makes it so easy so
we just scroll down a little bit and
then we're going to obviously click the
currency type that we have on the
account we're going to just fill out
this information it's going to literally
tell us how much we have to risk it's
going to tell us the lot size it's very
easy so we're going to put the account
size right now and we have a $5,000
account size so let's say you want to
risk a 10% of this account 5% 2% % 25%
whatever per you're okay with risking
everybody has a completely different
risk tolerance for this video example
let's just put 5% that we want to risk
now the stop- loss the amount of Pips
Pips is point in percentage also known
as points it's very simple so what we're
going to do is we're going to go back to
Euro USD and we're going to see how many
Pips is our stop loss as you guys can
see right here our stop loss is 81 Pips
that is how many points we're risking on
this trade and I again we can move this
up or down we can move this up we can
move it down for this example let's just
make it a solid
51 points or 50 points round so we come
here move it up move it down let's just
call it 51 points 51 Pips so this is
where we go back to the position size
calculator and our stop loss which is
what is this Zone in the red we're going
to Simply come here and we're going to
put 51 points then it's going to ask you
what currency pair are you trading on
are you trading on EUR USD are you
trading on gbpusd USD CHF so on and so
forth for this example we're going to
trade on Euro USD so here's where I
pretty much click calculate and it's
literally going to tell you the lot size
that you have to take on the trade it is
insane it's literally telling you the
amount of risk you have to take is
telling you the position size unit the
standard Lots the mini Lots the micro
Lots all that matters is the standard
Lots CU that is what we're trading on
The Meta Trader 5 so in this trade if
this trade goes immediately into your
stop loss you're going to lose
$250 no more it is impossible to lose
more than that because you have a stop-
loss you're going to obviously lose
probably 270 280 because the broker has
a spread they have their fees but that
is inevitable there's no way to avoid
that and if this trade goes into profit
you're then going to make money because
you're going to make $500 because you
have a positive risk to reward ratio so
what we do is every single time we take
a trade we come here we calculate the
risk then we go to medit four met tror 5
and we plug it in so there's never a
right lot size there's never the same
lot size because every single time it's
different all right so now we hop back
onto metat Trader 5 so you guys can see
here we just go back into metat Trader 5
and then we have our $5,000 account
balance which is the same one as our one
that we put in the position size
calculator we go back here to quotes we
pretty much click the Euro USD click
trade we've done this already and now
we're back here at the lot size so now
we go here to the lot size then we erase
the current lot size that we have so
we're going to put
0.5 which is exactly what the position
size calculator has shown us now this
position size calculator has shown us
that now we're going to be risking $5
per lot why $5 if it says 0.5 well
because the decimal point always moves
one point over so we move the decimal
point over that is going to be $5 per
lot if you multiply $5 time 50 it's
going to give us the
$250 that we're going to risk next we
have the actual stop loss so the stop
loss in order for us to find that we go
back here to trading View and in trading
view we can see that at the top of the
risk to reward ratio we have our stop-
loss so the stop- loss point is going to
be these red numbers right here so all
we have to do is copy those numbers
right there so as you can see it says
1.0
6065 so we're going to come here to the
metatrader 5 after we put in the lot
size we're going to put 1
06 065 so we know that as soon as we put
that stop loss price will never break
more than that point so we're never
going to lose more than what we are
risking then next is going to be our
take profit and our take profit is going
to be this line right here which is
going to be
1.0 it's going to be 1.0 3892 so 1.0
3892 and now we click sell or buy
obviously we know that the majority of
the market is heading to the downside so
we're going to Simply take a sell
position on this trade and as soon as we
click this sell button literally the
moment we click sell we're going to be
executed into the real Market there's
just something about this noise every
single time that it just excites me
because it means that we're in we're
trading we're live right so as soon as
you click the button so it makes that
noise and then you actually enter the
trade as of right now we're being
executed into the market and we're
currently about $4
down in price and you can always
consider that every single time you take
a trade you're going to be down about a
couple dollars depends on your lot size
because the broker has to charge the fee
they have to charge the spread that's
how they make money that's the favor
they're doing Us in order to execute us
into the real markets so now we're
obviously in this market and we pretty
much what we would do is set and forget
we would let this trade ride to our
takeprofit or we would let the trade
ride to our stop loss whichever one gets
hit first but now for this example
purposes we're going to close out the
trade because in real time if this
Market hits a stop loss or hits a
takeprofit it would take us out of the
position for us that's why we put the
stop loss that's why we put the
takeprofit but for this example we're
going to take out ourselves of the trade
so all we have to do is we have to just
simply hold the Euro USD option because
if you tap it this is going to happen so
you can tap it or hold it doesn't matter
so for this example we're just going to
tap it and it's going to say close
position modify trade depth of Market
chart the only button we care about is
close the position it's the only button
I ever really used and as soon as you
click close position it's going to close
you out immediately of this position so
as soon as you click close you're then
going to click close sell 0.5 at this
area with $11.50 of loss click that and
then you have accepted for that price to
then do that so now you can see that our
current balance is down by $2 so we're
pretty much still break even in order
for us to see the trade that we took and
what we've done we go to the History
Section and you can see how it's now
minus $2 on the EUR USD trade that we
have just taken and we've done it we've
literally analyzed the market together
we've spotted an area of support and
resistance we've identified a trend
that's been heading to the downside we
entered at an area of resistance that is
used as support and resistance to then
sell we've gone to the metatrader we've
created an account we've been able to
now identify the market we've been able
to put our lot Sid we've been able to
calculate our risk we've been able to
execute the trade and Clos the trade
we've done it all obviously this is just
a very beginner and very first step so
we've done everything to make money in
the markets now let's say instead of
losing those $2 let's say we would have
made $10 on this trade what do I do how
do I withdraw the money how do I get it
out of this metatrader 5 platform well
it's very easy the metatrader 5 platform
is connected to the broker it's an
extension of the broker it is what
connects you to the real market so that
money right there is technically not
yours as of right now it is in the
broker platform so all you have to do is
go to your broker and then you simply
just request withdraw oand is going to
give you withdraw straight back into
your bank account all you have to do is
just plug in your bank details and then
it is going to get your money back there
there's other platforms that they allow
crypto withdrawals and then crypto
deposits so you can just pretty much
plug in your Bitcoin address or your
usdt address and then the money goes
right into your crypto address and then
you do whatever you want with it there
but first you have to take the money out
of the metatrader fly platform and this
is an option that the broker is going to
give you so now let's say that we would
have made $10 on this $5,000 so that
means we would have been up $10 we would
have a total balance of $5,010 so that's
where we would go on to the broker and
then you would click withdraw of those
$10 so you're going to remove $10 from
this account once you remove $10 from
the account the balance on the metat
trador goes back to the starting balance
of $5,000 now you have these $10,000 in
your wallets inside your broker account
doesn't matter what happens to these
$5,000 on metatrader 5 doesn't matter if
you blow it or if you make more money
those $10 on your broker account are
safe they're not moving because they're
withdrawn from the market now they're
stored in a bank account within the
broker platform now what you have to do
is you have to go to this platform and
then you have to request to withdraw
that money into your bank account every
single broker has a different way to do
it but then they will all inevitably end
up to you because those are your
realized gains and that's it so it is
extremely easy to withdraw your profits
from the market so now what if you don't
actually have $5,000 to get started so
you deposit into your account and you
can make those $10 and obviously much
money much more well there's funding
this is what I mentioned at the
beginning of the video which you can
actually use other people's money to
make money in trading so there's many
funding companies out there but I only
and will forever recommend rocket 21
rocket 21 literally has the best
platform in order for you to be able to
go take the evaluation process you have
the easiest one-step evaluation process
in the world you have the easiest
twostep evaluation process in the world
with no time limits so you can take all
of the time that you want to take it so
what rocket 21 offers and many other
companies out there in the industry it
is access to funds that are not yours
without any risk so let's say you want
to seek a $5,000 account that rocket 21
has to offer because it is the only
platform out there that offers a $5,000
account to start off with instead of you
actually having to deposit $5,000 into
an account you just buy the challenge
the challenge will cost you 100 bucks
and instead of you putting a 100 bucks
into a platform and then using that you
could just simply go to Rocket 21 and
then you buy a challenge where now you
can leverage those $5,000 and you can
make much more profits with that money
because that way you're using other
people's money to make money in the
markets and as soon as you pass the
valuation process you get the $100 that
you PID for the challenge back now
you're literally free in the market so
you have $5,000 free that you have
literally access to do whatever you want
with it so you don't have to use your
own money if you don't have access to
let's say multiple thousands of dollars
there's many different types of funding
companies out there that offer funding
and this funding is the reason why I am
here today because I got a payout about
3 and 1/2 years ago where I literally
got
$28,000 from a funding company and that
made me enough cushion so I can leave my
job and I can literally just focus on
trading fulltime I didn't have money to
start off with I kept trying it with
small accounts but I kept blowing the
account and the way that I actually was
able to become profitable was by seeking
funding so this is a new version of
trading that is taking over and is
making Traders profitable month after
month and year after year so that's it
for this video right very simp simple
very straightforward video and I hope
you guys can now go into the market and
take your trade but if you want to
become like one of my students that
they're able to generate anywhere from
,000 to $1,500 a week using my set and
forget strategy in the first 3 months
just click the link in the description
below I have a video for you there that
explains what set and forget actually
consists of how hundreds if not
thousands of my students are been able
to now leave their job and retire early
how people that have full-time jobs are
able to make a living off of trade
and also go to their full-time job and
just use it as a side hustle and make
extra income so you want to know more
about what the center forget strategy is
what it consist of and how it lets
hundreds if not I think thousands of
Traders generate anywhere from ,000 to
$1,500 a week as a beginner Trader I'm
telling you just click the link in the
description below there's a video that
explains everything in a a lot more
detail because it simplifies not only
what I explained to you in this video
but it goes into more detail on what
senif foret is and how it's allowed me
to become financially free pretty much
trade from anywhere in the world and
change people's lives every single day
so I appreciate you guys watching this
video all the way to the end make sure
you guys click the link in the
description and I'll see you guys in the
next video